Raymond Cox

raymondcdev@gmail.com 937-205-6647 4846 Archdale Lane Columbus, Ohio

Summary

To further my professional career in a web or mobile development position. The ideal opportunity will be with a company that has strong leadership, a diverse team and career opportunities to advance with hard work. I plan to utilize my prior experience and education to be a dependable teammate while continuing to learn from experts.

Employment History

Software Developer

Vaultz Inc. • New Albany, Ohio

Began as a Front-End developer working alongside of the CEO to maintain a React-Native mobile application. Shortly after assumed role as the primary developer for the customer facing application, while CEO handled Back-End related work. Responsibilities include: Performing React-Native and imported library upgrades, Builds, Testing, and Deployment for both iOS and Android platforms alongside of general development including bug-fixes/features. Built a new React based web platform to integrate into our product and services.

Software engineer

Ascendum • Cincinnati, Ohio

12/2019 - 01/2020

06/2019 - Present

Implemented unit and end-to-end tests to 12 month old testless codebase through Jest and Detox. Performed multiple React Native version upgrades, while also making the app Android 64-bit compliant for Play Store.

Mobile Application Developer

CareSource • Dayton, Ohio

09/2018 - 06/2019

- Developed reusable components and libraries utilized across multiple company mobile applications.
- Built Enterprise-scale applications for Android and iOS through Java and Swift languages, as well as through React-Native framework.
- Assumed the Lead-Developer role in writing new Biometric Authentication feature for Enterprise Application.
- High affinity for writing and maintaining Unit and End to End Tests through Jest and Detox frameworks.
- Mentored other developers with Unit testing, features, implementation, debugging, building reusable libraries, as well as React-Native and JavaScript.
- Important contributions to feature implementation ideas and flows. Worked alongside Tech BA to outline story acceptance criteria where knowledgable.

Freelance Web Developer

Web Design By Raymond

11/2017 - 09/2018

Implementing design ideas through Front-End. Full-Stack web apps written in React.Js framework. Website redesigns and rewrites. Responsive design.

Professional Skills

• HTML5 • CSS3

- رىسىسى -
- Javascript
- E2E Testing
- React-Native
- Responsive Design
- Unity

- 000
- Unit Testing
- React
- Redux
- Version Control
- C#

Education

High School Diploma

North Adams High School • Seaman, Ohio

Graduated 05/2010